landandfarm.com 2014-06-25

# LandAndFarm.com - Privacy Statement

Effective Date Updated: May 06, 2013

LandAndFarm has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [www.LandAndFarm.com](http://www.landandfarm.com/). TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. When you visit a web site displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, you can expect to be notified of the following information:

  * The personal information collected and which organization is collecting the information
  * How the information is used and with whom the information may be shared
  * Choices available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  * Types of security procedures in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under the company's control
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [privacy@loopnet.com](mailto:privacy@loopnet.com). Alternatively, please contact us by mail at LandAndFarm Administration -- Privacy Statement, 2100 E. Route 66, Suite 200, Glendora, CA 91740, or by telephone at (626) 803-5000.

If the web site has not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint) . For more information on TRUSTe, please go to [http://www.truste.com](http://www.truste.com/).

**LandAndFarm’s Privacy Statement**

This privacy statement covers the website [http://www.LandAndFarm.com](http://www.landandfarm.com/). By accessing, using or registering with LandAndFarm's web site, you accept and agree to LandAndFarm's Privacy Statement. LandAndFarm provides a variety of online services for real estate professionals. LandAndFarm values your privacy, feedback and candor very highly. Any user information we collect is considered private and we do not use it or share it except as permitted herein, without the user's permission. We use this personal information at LandAndFarm to provide the best quality service possible. The following privacy statement summarizes LandAndFarm's protection and use of any personal information provided by visitors to the LandAndFarm site.

This statement does not apply to any public area of LandAndFarm's web site or services. In the event you submit personal information to contact another member, contact a lister about a listing, create a listing, add a contact on a listing, Professional Directory, Professional Profile, LandAndFarm Profile, such information becomes publicly available and LandAndFarm is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit to these services, forums, listings, or persons.

**Information Collected by LandAndFarm:**

LandAndFarm collects user information from several areas of the LandAndFarm site including the 'New Member Registration' area (where LandAndFarm collects each user's name, street address, telephone number, email address, and self-selected primary role in real estate); products; business services; the adding and editing of property listings; the adding and editing of Professional Profiles; email forms; and any surveys or contests that LandAndFarm may sponsor. LandAndFarm collects individual user search activity for statistical, archival, and business purposes. LandAndFarm collects financial information (such as billing address, credit card number, expiration date) for billing payment and credit card authorization purposes. LandAndFarm may track the IP address of a user's computer or place a "cookie" in the browser files of a user's computer. This is required by LandAndFarm services to provide automated features.

**Use of Information Collected:**

Collected information helps LandAndFarm better understand its users' needs in order to improve its product and service offerings. Email addresses are used to communicate with members, Promotional emails, Partner emails and for site administration purposes. Users may be deleted from Promotional email and Partner email lists at their request. Personal information may be used to contact users for the purpose of research, product development, marketing, or customer service, if the user has opted to receive such communication. User search activity is collected and analyzed and may be utilized by LandAndFarm in the aggregate or in the abstract for a variety of business purposes. Financial information is used to bill users for products and services purchased. Within LandAndFarm, only accounting managers have access to the credit card account information. This information is not shared with anyone outside of LandAndFarm. IP address and cookie log data is analyzed to better understand traffic flows and user preferences. LandAndFarm may retain the data it collects indefinitely. You may have your personal information deleted or deactivated by sending an email to [privacy@loopnet.com](mailto:privacy@loopnet.com). You may be asked to confirm your identity. You will receive a response within 10 business days.

**Use of Email Tools:**

You may NOT use the Email The Broker, Email a Listing service or other email services that we offer to send spam (i.e. unsolicited commercial email) or otherwise send content that would violate LandAndFarm's Terms and Conditions. We may monitor, track or save the use of this feature, but will be under no obligation to monitor, track or save these email messages sent from these tools. If you send and email using the Email This Item to a Friend service to an email address that is not registered in our system, we do not use that email address for any purpose other than to send your email, and for us to automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. LandAndFarm stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and for tracking the success of our referral program. We also do not rent or sell these email addresses of un-registered users.

Your friend may contact us at [privacy@loopnet.com](mailto:privacy@loopnet.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Shared information:**

Though LandAndFarm makes every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

LandAndFarm shares member information in the following areas on the site: Listing Service, Email Alerts and Professional Directory. When a member enters a sale or lease listing in the Listing Service, listing contact information is also entered. During this process, the listing submitter is able to view other members' contact information when he adds another contact beside himself to the listing. In addition, members searching LandAndFarm can view contact information (name, email and phone number) when they view a property listing profile. LandAndFarm allows users to share contact information with one another via its Email Alerts service. With Email Alerts users can save their property search criteria to have information about properties that match the specified criteria emailed to them. When selecting this service, users are given the option of releasing their contact information to other users who have property listings that match their criteria. This contact information is then shared with the users who have property listings that match the buying or leasing criteria. Unless required by law as detailed in this section or a user specifically takes action as discussed in this paragraph, LandAndFarm does not share individual user search activity information and such activity information remains private to the individual user and to LandAndFarm. Directory profile users agree to share their contact information and allow all LandAndFarm users to view their contact information via the LandAndFarm Professional Directory or via links made available to users on a listing or in an email. LandAndFarm users who do not opt out of the Professional Directory service during registration with LandAndFarm (or anytime thereafter) also agree to share their contact information via the LandAndFarm Professional Directory.

LandAndFarm shares information with its partners for the purpose of providing related services in which we deem our users have interest. The use that LandAndFarm's partners make of customer information will not exceed LandAndFarm's use of the data. Key billing information (such as credit card number, expiration date and dollar amount) gathered from users making online purchases of products or services is shared with VeriSign, our credit card processing partner, in order to authorize charges to the credit card. LandAndFarm also uses third party providers to perform email and postal mailings on behalf of LandAndFarm, but this information (such as name, address and email) is confidential and is not used by the provider for any other purpose.

LandAndFarm does not rent or lease user information to any third party, except as disclosed here. From time to time, LandAndFarm may obtain information (such as electronic mail addresses) from third party providers. It is our goal to only contact individuals who we believe may have a legitimate business interest in LandAndFarm based on their membership or participation in other organizations or web sites, and who have indicated a willingness to be contacted for this purpose. While LandAndFarm endeavors to work with other sites and companies with a similar respect for user privacy, LandAndFarm cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of other sites.

Please be aware that in the event LandAndFarm merges with a third party, or in the event all or substantially all of LandAndFarm's assets are acquired by a third party, customer information, including personal information, will be shared and/or transferred to such third party. The information may only be used or shared by such third parties for the primary purpose for which the information was originally collected. If such third parties, or if LandAndFarm for its own business needs, desire to use the personal information for another purpose, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information prior to the information being used for a new purpose, and you will have the opportunity to opt out of such new use of your personal information.

**Security of personal information:**

LandAndFarm's clients and their personal information are considered to be LandAndFarm's greatest asset and thus their privacy is treated with the utmost regard and respect. LandAndFarm takes every reasonable precaution to secure personal information within both its computers and its physical premises.

The security of your personal information is important to LandAndFarm. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). [To learn more about SSL, follow this link [http://www.verisign.com](http://www.verisign.com/)].

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at [privacy@loopnet.com](mailto:privacy@loopnet.com).

**Cookies:**

Cookies are used on this site. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes.

We use both session cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to use our site and to enable certain specialized functionality that requires maintaining information about your session. A session cookie is not stored on your hard disk and expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard disk for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following the directions in your Internet browser's "help" files.

If you select the "Remember Me" function on the web site, we will store a persistent cookie on your hard drive which allows you to bypass the login requirement each time you access the site. Additionally, we use a persistent cookie to enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

We do not store in persistent cookies any personal information you submit while on our site.

Due to the functionality provided by our site, the use of cookies is required. If you reject cookies, our site will not perform properly.

**Web Beacons / Gifs**

We employ [or our third party advertising partner employs] a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personal information. To learn more about our advertising company’s use of clear gifs, you can email us at [privacy@loopnet.com](mailto:privacy@loopnet.com).

**Flash LSOs**

We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences such as volume control, or display content based upon what you view on our site to personalize your visit. Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information.

Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:

<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

**3 RD Party Tracking**

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company or service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company or service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.

**Third-Party Advertising Companies**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. The third-party advertising technology that we use on this Web site uses information derived from your visits to this site to target advertising within this site. In addition, our advertisers may use other third-party advertising technology to target advertising on this site and other sites. In the course of advertisements being served to you, a unique third-party cookie or cookies may be placed your browser. In addition, we may use Web beacons, provided by third-party advertising companies, to help manage and optimize our online advertising. Web beacons enable us to recognize a browser's cookie when a browser visits this site, and to learn which banner ads bring users to our Web site. To "opt-out," please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp) or visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp>.

**Testimonials:**

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personal information such as the customer's name. We do obtain the customer's consent to post their name along with their testimonial prior to any posting of such testimonial. To request removal of your personal information from these testimonials, contact us at [LandAndFarm Client Services](http://www.landandfarm.com/contact/contactus/). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Blog / Forum**

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [LandAndFarm Client Services](http://www.landandfarm.com/contact/contactus/). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Twitter button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

**Links to 3 rd Party Sites**

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of LandAndFarm. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.

**Opting-out, editing, updating or deleting personal information:**

LandAndFarm utilizes email as a vital and primary communication channel with registered users and customers. As a registered user/customer, you hereby acknowledge and grant LandAndFarm the permission to communicate with you via email (as well as other communication channel such as phone, fax or social media) for any purposes LandAndFarm determines to be relevant including, but not limited to, system messages, product updates, service announcements and other marketing messages. LandAndFarm will use best efforts to honor customers request to opt out of marketing messages, but under no circumstances will LandAndFarm have any liability for sending any email to its registered users/customers.

Users who do not wish to receive marketing emails including LandAndFarm Promotional Emails, or Sponsor Emails are requested to contact [LandAndFarm Client Services](http://www.landandfarm.com/contact/contactus/) via email, or select the opt-out option by deselecting the email option from their member profile. We also send our users site and service announcement updates. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about service notices and responsibilities. LandAndFarm occasionally communicates with its users via email and phone to provide information about requested services and regarding issues related to their account. It is important to note that this communication is not used for marketing or promotional purposes. Requesting the deletion of certain types of user information may prevent users from accessing some web site features.

You may correct or update your personal information by making the change on your member profile page.

Subscriptions will automatically renew using the Customer's current credit card account number unless Customer cancels their subscription on the My Properties Page of the LandAndFarm Web site at <http://www.landandfarm.com/lf/aspclient/myproperties_classic.asp> three (3) days prior to the renewal date to cancel such subscription. All cancellation requests will be processed within five (5) business days. Once the cancellation is processed, a confirmation email will be sent via the customer's email account on record with LandAndFarm. If Customer has a question about a cancellation, Customer should contact LandAndFarm Client Services at Customer-Service@LandAndFarm.com or at (888) 327-6289. The Company reserves the right to change its fees or billing methods at any time. The Company will provide timely notice to the affected Customers of any such changes.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us using the form on the [LandAndFarm Contact Us page](http://www.landandfarm.com/contact/contactus/). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Notification Procedures:**

LandAndFarm may provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice (including via fax), or through posting of such notice on our website, as determined by LandAndFarm in our sole discretion. LandAndFarm reserves the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to our users, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described herein. LandAndFarm is not responsible for any automatic filtering you or your network provider may apply to email notifications we send to the email address you provide us. We recommend that you add Customer-Service@LandAndFarm.com to your email address book to help ensure you receive email notifications from us.

**Changes to this Privacy Statement:**

If LandAndFarm decides to change its privacy statement, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

LandAndFarm reserves the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If LandAndFarm makes material changes to this statement, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.
